Preliminary Inventory to the Russia. Voennyĭ Agent (France) Records, 1835-1876
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia. Voennyĭ Agent (France) Records,
1835-1876
29003
Russia. Voennyi agent (France)
6 manuscript boxes (2.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, studies, lists, charts, and printed matter, relating to military relations between Russia and France
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1929.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Russia. Armiia; France; France--Military relations--Russia; Russia; Russia--Military relations--France; Military attachés
Container List
- Office of the Russian Military Attaché in Paris, 1835-1876
  - Correspondence of the Russian Minister of War with the Russian Embassy in Paris, 1835-38 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence with Count Chernyshev, 1838
  - Private correspondence between Count Chernyshev and Mr. Von Spiess, 1st Secretary of the Russian Embassy in Paris, 1839-1841 (Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence between the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg, and the Russian Embassy in Paris
    - 1842-45 (Folder 5-6)
    - 1846-47 (Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg, and the Russian Military Attaché, Count Stackelberg, 1848-1850 (Folder 8)
  - Documents and notes of various individuals, 1849-1850 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Memorandum on Dutch artillery and Delft fortifications, 1850
  - Correspondence between the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg, the Artillery Department, St. Petersburg, and the Russian Consul General, Paris, 1850-54 (Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg, and the Russian Military Attaché, Count Stackelberg, 1850-52 (Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous documents and notes of the Russian Military Attaché, Count Stackelberg, 1850-52 (Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence between the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg, various individuals, and the Russian Military Attaché, Count Stackelberg, 1846-1850 (Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg, various individuals, and the Russian Military Attaché, Count Stackelberg (Box 3)
    - 1846-1850 (Folder 1)
    - 1851-54 (Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence between the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg, and the Russian Consul General, Paris, Mr. Von Spiess, 1848-49 (Folder 4-5)
  - Copies of letters sent by the Russian Military Attaché, Paris, to the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg
    - 1835-39 (Folder 6)
    - 1840-42 (Folder 7)
    - 1840-42 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with the Russian War Office, St. Petersburg
    - 1861-62 (Folder 2-3)
    - 1863 (Folder 4-5)
    - 1864 (Folder 6-7)
    - 1865 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - 1866 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1867 (Folder 5-6)
    - 1868 (Folder 7)
    - 1868 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1869-1871 (Folder 2)
    - 1872-73 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1874-76 (Folder 5)